<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Text, Editor</title><link href="https://rveeblfetzer.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rveeblfetzer.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rveeblfetzer.github.io/</id><updated>2018-11-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Reinitializing...</title><link href="https://rveeblfetzer.github.io/2018/11/15/reinitializing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rick Valenzuela</name></author><id>tag:rveeblfetzer.github.io,2018-11-15:/2018/11/15/reinitializing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Burn it down, start all over. I've hit this point so often, it's almost like my
MO for learning a new thing. And it's not bad, either. Among the pluses are a
cathartic release for frustrations over whatever snag I hit, the building of
muscle memory for the parts I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Burn it down, start all over. I've hit this point so often, it's almost like my
MO for learning a new thing. And it's not bad, either. Among the pluses are a
cathartic release for frustrations over whatever snag I hit, the building of
muscle memory for the parts I didn't screw up, and a clean, fresh start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally made this space on an old laptop I used to test drive Arch Linux.
Sometime shortly after, I moved continents, and a lot got put on hold.
Somewhere along the way, I lost a password manager file. Or maybe I didn't
even; that install was more less a disposable lab, so the password could've
been on paper, or just something simple I remembered. Whatever it was, it was
gone. For the last couple weeks, I've booted and stared at that machine,
eventually remembering the passphrase to decrypt the disk, only to get stumped
at the login. In that laptop was the repo to this blog. The contents of the
site were retrievable, on a remote repo on Github, but the config and templates
were somewhere behind the greeter page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a change of pace, my project faced a controlled burn not because of
technical error, but negligence. Luckily, Pelican is really easy to sort out,
and I had opted for mostly prebuilt aesthetics. There wasn't anything to
redesign, just pull the CSS from the site. So the optimistic me frames the
experience as re-familiarizing myself with the Pelican config and Jinja2, and
learning my lesson to better maintain and back up my password manager. And
since that laptop didn't have much else on it, I can now burn down the install
that's there and go through the Arch install process again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>init</title><link href="https://rveeblfetzer.github.io/2018/03/22/init.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rick Valenzuela</name></author><id>tag:rveeblfetzer.github.io,2018-03-22:/2018/03/22/init.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aaaaand, here I am, learning &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; to make a blog. And writing in reStructuredText, to practice using Python's official markup syntax. Because part of the aim in making this was to learn something new, and that's kind of already over for Pelican. It's not a huge framework; it's a light …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aaaaand, here I am, learning &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; to make a blog. And writing in reStructuredText, to practice using Python's official markup syntax. Because part of the aim in making this was to learn something new, and that's kind of already over for Pelican. It's not a huge framework; it's a light static-site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could've done this thing in Django, Flask or Pyramid, but those are all heavy hammers for what I need. It's just my scribblings and the occasional image. No one else to log in and auth; no database, just pages. No real application logic to secure, and backing up is a breeze. Best of all, I can write in my terminal, just from the home row and no clicking around the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's so easy to set up, though, it feels like cheating. But it's the right tool for the job, and it gets me quicker to the actual work of putting the words in here. &lt;span class="emoji"&gt;🔩&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="emoji"&gt;🔧&lt;/span&gt; And I could use the extra time to work out the rST syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>