<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Text, Editor - Python</title><link href="https://rveeblfetzer.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rveeblfetzer.github.io/feeds/python.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rveeblfetzer.github.io/</id><updated>2018-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>init</title><link href="https://rveeblfetzer.github.io/2018/03/22/init.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rick Valenzuela</name></author><id>tag:rveeblfetzer.github.io,2018-03-22:/2018/03/22/init.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aaaaand, here I am, learning &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; to make a blog. And writing in reStructuredText, to practice using Python's official markup syntax. Because part of the aim in making this was to learn something new, and that's kind of already over for Pelican. It's not a huge framework; it's a light …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aaaaand, here I am, learning &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; to make a blog. And writing in reStructuredText, to practice using Python's official markup syntax. Because part of the aim in making this was to learn something new, and that's kind of already over for Pelican. It's not a huge framework; it's a light static-site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could've done this thing in Django, Flask or Pyramid, but those are all heavy hammers for what I need. It's just my scribblings and the occasional image. No one else to log in and auth; no database, just pages. No real application logic to secure, and backing up is a breeze. Best of all, I can write in my terminal, just from the home row and no clicking around the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's so easy to set up, though, it feels like cheating. But it's the right tool for the job, and it gets me quicker to the actual work of putting the words in here. &lt;span class="emoji"&gt;🔩&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="emoji"&gt;🔧&lt;/span&gt; And I could use the extra time to work out the rST syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>